NO ENTRY
(禁止进入)
Leave it to me!
交给我吧
That took long enough. I can finally take a nap.
真是的 终于能睡午觉了
I told you not to rush to the front line.
跟你们说了别到前线
Our mission was to stop the Others's advance.
只要阻止怪异的前进就好了
Yes...
是…
Sorry, Captain Shiden.
对不起 紫电队长
Well done, Captain Shiden.
辛苦啦 紫电队长
You should take a break sometimes, Captain Shiden.
你也找时间偷个懒吧 紫电队长
Shut it.
吵死了
I knew I'd become a captain someday.
我早就想到 总有一天能当上队长
Train the new recruits and pay attention to their performances,
教育新人 注意每位队员
those are what a captain does.
这就是队长的工作
Kasane was supposed to be the captain.
原本应该由重继续当队长
Do you want her to take your place?
想跟她换吗
Not a chance.
怎么可能
Besides, she got her hands full already.
而且她有她的工作要做
I can't ask her to take over the platoon.
哪有跟她换的道理…
What are you discussing?
你们在说什么
What brings you here?
妳怎么来了
You're not working here today, right?
今天的工作地点不在这吧
I'm here to submit a progress report.
我来做进度报告
I heard you discussing me.
你们 在说我什么
It was nothing.
什么都没有
We were talking about what makes a good captain.
只是在说如何当个好队长
Do you have other plans today?
还有其他行程吗
Yuito is coming here today.
今天结人要来
I'll go pick him up.
我去接他
Thanks.
谢谢
Kasane, it's been a while.
重 好久不见
It's nice to see you again.
好久不见
You seem to do very well.
你看起来很有精神
SCARLET NEXUS
《绯红结系》
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
倦怠感 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
尚未找到建立关系的方法吗
♫It’s my awkward friend’s fault♫
有个麻烦的朋友
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
至死都在寻求某人的拥抱
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
在得以喘息的混沌虚无之间
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
以输赢之间为目标
♫Not to be running out of patience for now, I’m trying to be careful♫
注意别让信任走向尽头 务必小心
♫You’ll see I’m always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地联系着
♫You’re frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
你脑中那冷感的轨道
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
摇滚的日子未曾有过的浩劫
♫Where is the glory buried?♫
光荣早已埋葬在某处
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
这一瞬间寂寞孤独的野兽
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
与机关枪射出的子弹并列
♫To pierce with the theory♫
射穿所有世间道理
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地联系着
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
与机关枪射出的子弹并列
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天也仍在一起 清晰地联系着
♫You’re frigid and the theory in the brain♫
你那脑中冷感的正义
"EVERYONE'S FUTURE" It's not being used anymore, don't worry.
(各自的未来) 已经不用了 别勉强
You should listen to your doctor.
你还是乖乖听医生的话
Did you choose to do this?
真的是妳自愿的吗
Yes.
是啊
Where is Arashi?
岚呢
She said this place was too noisy to take a nap.
她说这里太吵 睡不着
Are you here for the retirement paperwork?
你是来…办退伍手续的啊
I also came here to check on everyone.
顺便跟大家打个招呼
I see a lot of new faces around here.
这里多了许多新面孔
There have been many new recruits.
毕竟有许多新人加入
The Extinction Belt is gone,
虽然断绝之带消失了
but there are still come remaining Others.
但怪异仍存在
I heard Shiden became a captain.
紫电 听说你当队长了
How are you doing?
没问题吗
I'm doing just fine.
那当然
I'll become a major general or even the chief.
之后我还会当上连队长 甚至是本部长
You? As the chief?
你当上本部长吗
The tension between Suoh and Seiran has never ended.
苏芳和青蓝之间的对立尚未平息
There should be more cooperation between the two cities.
必须加深彼此之间的都市合作
The people will be in a lot of trouble if someone who doesn't know it becomes a leader.
让不懂这些重要性的人当上级 可是会给众人带来麻烦的
I plan to keep going on missions before I received the official retirement order.
我打算收到退役命令前 继续执行任务
I'll make sure OSF won't go astray again.
避免怪伐军再次走向错误的方向
I feel relieved with you guys around.
有你们在 就能放心了
You're welcome to drop by anytime.
欢迎你随时来找我们
Should we throw another dumpling party?
要不要 再举办一次煎饺派对啊
Suit yourself, just don't order too much food.
随便啦 但这次别再点太多了
To the destruction of Kunad Gate, cheers!
庆祝岐之门消失 干杯
Cheers!
干杯
The dumplings were delicious,
煎饺虽然很好吃
but there were too many of them.
但那次真的点太多了
You ate plenty of them yourself.
你不也吃了很多吗
I don't waste food for no good reason.
我是个不浪费食物的人
Have you seen Hanabi?
你见过花火了吗
No, I haven't.
不 还没
Alice Platoon will be on patrol missions.
艾丽斯小队还要执行巡逻任务
Go to her now if you want to see her.
要见她最好动作快
You're right. Thanks.
说的也是 谢谢
Alice Platoon...
艾丽斯小队…
Hanabi, Tsugumi.
花火 鸫
Yuito.
结人
How is your family?
妳老家 还好吗
Regarding the inhumane experiment conducted at the OSF hospital,
关于在怪伐军医院 实施的非人道实验
-the chief of the hospital has... -What my uncle did at the facility
-该医院院长… -叔叔在医院做过的事
was never known to my parents.
我父母也不知情
They were more worried about me, actually.
他们反而更担心我
There is a challenging future ahead for the Ichijo family.
一条家之后可能会很艰辛
But perhaps that's for the best.
不过 这样应该算好的吧
But things are even tougher for Captain Alice.
但艾丽斯队长的处境就很两难了…
That's because the Chairman of OSF hospital
因为怪伐军医院的理事长
is Captain Alice's elder brother.
是艾丽斯队长的哥哥
How are you holding up, Yuito?
结人呢 你还好吗
Chief Sumeragi has been replaced.
皇本部长 被换掉了
Based on his statement during the hearing,
根据哥哥在听证会提出的证词
he will face punishment.
应该会受到处分吧
The Extinction Belt may be gone now,
即便消除了断绝之带
but the Sumeragi family has faced public uproar.
但皇家仍受到强烈批判
But still, we cannot dwell on the past.
然而 我们不能总是活在过去
I agree.
我也是
Even though I was scouted into the OSF,
虽然我是被招募加入怪伐军的
but fighting along everyone
但我认为能跟大家一起战斗
and creating a better future for the sake of New Himuka
为了众人 一同让新日向
is still very meaningful.
走向好的未来是好事
After the Extinction Belt has been eliminated,
断绝之带消失后
the sunlight has become warmer.
我感觉 太阳的温度 比以往更暖和了
The plants are very happy.
植物们都感到很高兴
I will do my best to give them
为了让他们能静静地生活
a peaceful life.
我会继续努力的
Kasane, Yuito,
重 结人
how are you holding up?
身体好多了吗
I heard you are retiring. We're going to miss you.
你要退伍啦 我们会觉得寂寞喔
Yuito, check this out.
结人 你听我说喔
Major General Fubuki and Captain Alice
吹雪连队长和艾丽斯队长
are finally getting married.
他们要结婚了
The marriage was arranged a long time ago.
我们很早以前就有婚约了
It's not really that big of a surprise.
所以 也没什么好惊讶的
We'll be sure to attend your wedding.
婚礼时 我们一定会去参加的
I'll make the bouquet for you.
我来做捧花吧
Well, that is one way to say it...
话虽如此… 对吧
Yeah, now is not the right time for a wedding.
是啊 目前还不适合举办婚礼
You can invite only the people from HQ.
只有我们总部成员参加也行
I'll consider that idea.
我会好好考虑的
Yuito, Kasane, see you around.
结人 重 回头见
You people are always so noisy.
真是静不下来啊
Arashi...
岚
I'm glad you're finally discharged, Yuito.
结人 恭喜你出院
Well, that's one burden taken off my shoulder.
这样 我也能放下肩上的重担了
You must be really worried about Major General Fubuki.
其实妳还是很担心 连队长吧
I don't have the time to be concerned about his business.
我才没那闲功夫去担心他呢
Congratulations on the promotion, Major General Luka.
恭喜你当上连队长
Are you really retiring?
你真的要退伍啦
What will you do next?
之后有什么打算呢
I'm going to college.
我打算去上大学
I want to learn more about the world.
学习许多知识
I see.
这样啊
I'm going to do my best
我也打算尽我所能
to help make this country a better place
以怪伐军的身分尽其义务
as a member of the OSF.
为改变这个国家尽心工作
What is your plan?
改变 怎么改变
This country is not a friendly place for Bell Peppers.
这个国家 对甜椒十分不友善
Our system has ignored them completely.
几乎没为他们的生活做考虑
We pretend like they don't exist at all.
他们就像不存在一般
Without brain power, they can't see anything.
只要没有脑力 根本看不到画面
I had gone through that as a kid.
小时候 我也是这样
In order to develop my power,
而为了开发出超脑力
I spent every day inside the lab
每天 在实验室里
and suffered in loneliness.
一个人 饱受痛苦…
-Luka? -What's wrong?
-鲁卡 -怎么了
Wait...
不…
I think there was a boy just like me who was also a test subject.
好像有个男生 跟我一样是被实验体
I managed to survive those experiments thanks to him.
因为有他在 我才能撑过那些痛苦的实验
But now, I can't even remember his name.
可是 我甚至连他的名字 都不记得了
I see.
这样啊
Anyway, let's hope for the best for everyone.
总之 我们互相加油吧
Yes.
好
You too, Kasane. We don't know how the project will go,
重也是 虽不知那个计划会如何
but don't push yourself too hard.
但不要勉强喔
Yeah, I understand.
好 我知道
It seems everyone has really forgotten him.
大家 真的都忘记了
They don't remember anything about Karen.
忘记卡连了…
On that day, history was rewritten.
那天 历史改变了
We did it, Fubuki.
成功了 吹雪
Alice...
爱…艾丽斯…
Why are we the only people who remember Karen?
为何 只有我们记得卡连
Is it because we connected ourselves to Yuito and Kasane through SAS?
会不会是用SAS 跟结人和重连结的缘故
Just like the wielder of Red Strings,
跟红色系线脑力者一样
we have become the people who can observe the world.
我们也成为"观测世界"的一方
Yuito, how is your body holding up?
结人 身体情况还好吗
Don't worry about me.
别担心
I stopped having headache after that day.
那之后我就不会头痛
I can use my power with no problem.
超脑力也能顺利施展
Is it because the Kunad Gate has been destroyed?
是不是因为岐之门消失的缘故
Whatever the case is, this is great.
总之 太好了
Yeah.
是啊
Yes, keep it up.
很好 就是这样
Hanabi, a little to the front!
花火 再往前一点
Yes.
是
I still can't get used to having Alice in the team.
我还不习惯 有艾丽斯的日常
What are you talking about?
说什么啊
She's been here since you joined the force.
从你入伍开始她就在了啊
You may be from the other platoon, but...
就算你是别的小队的人…
She's always been here...
她一直都在…
What were we talking about just now?
刚才 我们在说什么
You mentioned the causality between Karen's time jump
妳曾说过卡连做了时间跳跃 与艾丽斯还活着
and Alice being alive all this time.
这两件事 有着因果关系吧
Did you find anything else after that?
那之后 有什么进展吗
In other words, the incident caused a massive butterfly effect.
总之 就是起了巨大的蝴蝶效应
But we have no way to prove it.
但没有证据就是了
He sacrificed himself to create a miracle.
以自身换来奇迹吗…
Who sacrificed himself?
谁…换来了奇迹
It's Karen.
卡连啊
Karen?
卡连
I guess that's it.
应该就这样吧
But I don't like making baseless assumptions.
但我不喜欢没有根据的说法
Karen is slowly being wiped from everyone's memories.
卡连似乎渐渐从大家的记忆中消失
You are right.
就是啊…
At this rate...
再这样下去…
Yuito! Yuito!
结人…
In the end, only we remember the whole story.
最后 除了我们
Karen has been erased from everyone's memories.
其他人都忘了卡连
This is the world he wanted to create.
这就是 卡连所期望的世界
Other than Alice being alive,
除了艾丽斯还活着
everything else remains unchanged.
其他都跟之前一样
Even so, I still think Karen's was wrong.
即便如此 我仍觉得卡连的作法是错的
Changing the history for the sake of a loved one
为了某人改变历史
should not be allowed.
这是不该被允许的
The world has changed.
世界改变了
But still, we are alive.
然而 我们活了下来
Karen was the one who created this reality.
开创现今历史的人 或许是卡连
But we will
但是
create the future for ourselves.
创造未来的人 是我们
Yes.
没错
We'll create our own future.
创造 我们的未来
Sorry for the long wait.
让妳久等了
Thanks.
谢谢
Fubuki.
吹雪
Who is that coffee for?
那是给谁的
Kasane, you are still a soldier of OSF.
重 妳在怪伐军里还留有军阶吧
Yes. I'll retain my ranks until the other preparation is complete.
是啊 到那边准备好为止
The saviors of our country are here.
救国英雄出来啦
Or should I say "traitors?"
又或是 叛国贼呢
Kagero and Kyoka?
阳炎 镜花
I'm glad to see you're doing well, Yuito.
结人 你看起来很有精神
Are you two taking part in the Moon investigation?
两位都要协助月面调查计划吗
Yes. The New Himuka government wanted our help.
是啊 新日向政府拜托我们的
We disbanded the Togestsu Faith too.
顺便解散渡月教
When BABE stopped operating, the cryosleep devices also stopped.
贝比停止时 冷冻睡眠装置似乎也停止了
All the immigrants from Moon woke up.
沉睡的移民团全部都醒了
Without BABE, they are not a threat.
只要没有贝比 他们就没什么能耐
The government has no records of you two being Togetsu spies.
政府的纪录里 也消除了两人是间谍的事
It was a deal between the adults.
大人之间的交易嘛
They will require the knowledge and information you have.
这就表示 需要两位的知识与情报
Yes. If the information we have can help in any way,
是啊 我们提供的情报 能派上用场的话
the government will have our full support.
我们会倾力相助的
And Yuito, regarding our father...
结人 还有你父亲的事
My father...
我父亲
Chairman Sumeragi knew about those inhuman experiments.
皇议长 知道那些违反人道的事
But he also protected New Himuka from Togetsu.
不过 他守护了新日向 不被渡月所侵害
We will spread the word around.
这些事 我们也会传达的
Thank you, Kyoka.
镜花 谢谢妳
Kagero, what will you do
如果调查计划顺利的话
if everything goes well after the project?
阳炎有什么打算
What do you mean?
什么意思
Will you go back to the Moon if you can?
如果能回去的话 你会回月球吗
I no longer have the intention to go back there.
想回去的心情早就没了
Don't you have a reason to go back there?
你对月球没有遗憾了吗
I am concerned about
留在月球的家人
my family on the Moon
现在的月球是什么状况
and what the place has become.
虽然这些都很在意
But there is no way to go back there just yet.
不过 又还没确定能回去
I'm glad Kagero decided to help.
阳炎愿意帮忙的话真是太好了
You are at the top of the command chain of the immigrants,
毕竟移民团 算是军队中的最高司令官嘛
General Shin Daniel.
辛丹尼尔将军
Don't call me that.
别这样叫我
Isn't that your real name?
那是你的本名吧
We are counting on you, General.
拜托你啰 将军
People from ancient times can be such a pain in the neck.
古代人很麻烦的耶
They left behind all those files.
留下了一堆资料
What was that, General?
将军 您说什么
Nothing.
什么都没有
What's wrong, Hanabi?
花火 怎么了
Is there no way for Yuito's power...
结人的超脑力 已经…
It can't be restored.
无法恢复了吧
If we could stop it back then...
当时 我们能阻止的话…
It wouldn't make a difference.
阻止也没用吧
Without Yuito, all of this...
没有结人的话 现在已经…
I know that!
我当然知道
But what is wrong with Kasane?
不过 重也是
What is she thinking anyway?
到底在想什么
Are you really going to the Moon?
妳真的要去 月球吗
Yes, I want to be there.
是啊 我要去
I'm worried about Kasane too.
我也很担心重
Is she really going to the Moon?
他说要去月球 这是真的吗
There are a lot of technologies and information left behind by the immigrants in Togetsu.
渡月里留下了移民团的技术和资料
We have the resources.
只要使用这些…
However...
可是…
We don't know what the Moon has become.
月球的现况
The worst case is that it's now crawling with Others.
最惨的情况 可能是已变成满是怪异的世界
Even so, Kasane insists on going there.
即便如此 重仍然要去
She's even going there alone.
而且是一个人去
I heard that you volunteered to be the advance team.
听说妳自愿当先遣队
We don't know how it is on the Moon.
因为不知月球的现况
So I must take point.
所以我先过去
We can just send the drones.
可以让无人观测机去啊
You don't have to...
没必要让妳…
If I run into people who are attacked by Others,
如果 遇到被怪异袭击的人
I can save them with my power.
有超脑力者在就能得救
Someone must go there first.
所以总得有人过去
But still...
可是…
I hate that feeling.
我很不甘心
I don't want to have any regret.
我不想再后悔了
I won't just stand and do nothing while people die.
我不想再眼睁睁地看着有人丧命
Not anymore...
我不想了…
Kasane...
重
I knew this would happen to you.
我明知道 也晓得 你会变成现在这样
But I insisted on making you fight
但我还是勉强你战斗
and made you responsible...
让你背负责任
I...
我… 我…
I hate that feeling as well.
我也不甘心
I just can't accept it!
不甘心 真的很不甘心
Nagi and I had a promise.
我跟那岐说好
We promised to become great soldiers.
要成为了不起的怪伐军
But why...
可是 为什么…
Yuito.
结人
I'm sorry, I...
对不起 我…
I don't want to have any regret.
我也不想后悔
I've made up my mind.
所以我决定了
Kasane, I'm going to become a politician.
重 我要成为政治家
I want to build a country where its people won't be monitored
我想创造政府不会监控人民
and lied to by the government.
不会对人民说谎的国家
I want to make life better for Bell Peppers.
还要考虑到甜椒的生活
I want to research on the Other particles.
以及研究兽粒子
But the Extinction Belt is gone.
已经没有断绝之带了
There could be a way to turn people back to normal after metamorphosis.
但或许能让怪异化的人恢复
Yuito...
结人
I'll create a better future.
我要成为政治家 创造未来
The OSF can do better.
怪伐军 应成为更好的组织
We should be able to retire if we choose to.
能以自己的想法而中途退伍
Even if you could, you wouldn't,
就算能 你也不想中途退伍吧
-right, Shiden? -Of course.
-紫电 -废话
You're the future chief after all.
到你当上本部长为止吗
It has nothing to do with this.
跟这没关系
I don't know how far up I'll reach,
虽不清楚我能走到哪一步
but I'll try my best!
但我仍然…
Me too.
我也是
I'm not sure how much longer this body can hold up,
虽不知我的身体能撑到何时
but before that,
但到那天之前
I won't stop fighting.
我仍想继续战斗
We aren't that different from Kasane when you think about it.
我们跟想去月球的重 其实也没什么两样嘛
Yuito must have his own plans as well.
结人应该也有所打算
He's not the kind who would settle down.
毕竟他不是会甘于现况的家伙
He might actually become a politician.
搞不好会走上政治家的道路喔
We can't let Kasane and Yuito get ahead of us.
不能输给重和结人
To think that ignorant brat will become a politician...
那个天真的家伙碰政治啊…
Perhaps you could show him the way, General.
不然你多教教他吧 将军
That's right! You can be his mentor.
没错 可以当结人的家教啊
How does that sound, General?
如何 将军
That is a great idea, General.
这个点子不错 将军
Give it a rest.
饶了我吧
I must go now and do my best to help.
我要去 为了尽我自己所能
I wouldn't expect anything less from you.
真像你的作风
You could be a great politician.
政治家 也很适合你啊
Honestly, I'm not very sure about that.
老实说 我没什么自信
But I have made up my mind.
不过我已经下定决心了
Thank you, Kasane.
重 谢谢你
I didn't do anything.
我也没帮什么…
Honestly, I feel worried.
老实说 我也很不安
But even when I'm alone,
不过 就算只有我一人
I feel motivated knowing that everyone
想到你 还有大家都在努力
is still giving their all for the world.
我就有动力了
Perhaps it's changing the world is an inflated thought.
改变世界 这个说法或许很夸张
We've saved the world once,
既然都拯救过世界了
I'm sure we can change it for the better.
也定能改变世界
I'm going to college while you are going to the Moon.
我去上大学 重去月球
We will be a great distance between us,
虽然相隔遥远
but we are still in the same world.
但我们都在同一个世界里
I'll leave this place in your care.
这里就交给你啰
Sure, you can count on me.
好 交给我吧
I'll live on.
我会在这里 好好活下去
Others have been spotted in area E-24.
E-24地区出现怪异
Haruka...
遥
Alice Platoon, head to the area immediately.
艾丽斯小队立刻去现场
Shiden Platoon, moving out.
紫电小队 出动
Let's go, everyone.
好 大家走吧
I'm coming with you.
我也去吧
Are you going too?
妳要去吗
I'm still a member of OSF.
我现在还是怪伐军的成员
Each of us is a unique individual.
每个人都是不同的个体
However,
不过
people can be connected with each other.
人与人之间都能互相连结
You can be alone, but not lonely.
即便是一个人 但也绝非一个人
YOU'VE RECEIVED A MESSAGE
(收到讯息 检查完毕)
YUITO SUMERAGI
(结人皇)
KAITO
(界人)
No matter how far apart we are...
无论分隔多远
Even if we can't see each other...
就算 抵达无法相见的地方
We are...
我们…
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
被追求的憧憬所困
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
揭开被阻挡的摇曳阳炎
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
从未见过
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
自己能不再恐惧翱翔高空
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
华丽舞步的鸟儿
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
仰望染红的天空
♫I chased after the gust♫
追过了强风
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
景色蔓延在千变万化的世界里
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
在交错的光芒中
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
持续寻找明天的行径方向
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
前进
♫Have no fear for anything♫
不再畏惧何物
♫Now, let's go♫
走吧
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day